ICS Lombard in Focus the insurance
player reported a strong q1 with a 49%
jump in profits my colleague harsh sa
caught up with the management to decode
their q1 earnings listen
in um I think if you look at it from a
market standpoint uh the industry has
been kind of generally growing at
anywhere between about 14 to 15% again
if you look at across various periods
but more importantly I think if you look
at the overall industry bottom line in
terms of the combined ratios that that
is still at uh as in for the last year
ended exit the industry for fi 24 had a
combined ratio of 112 this of course is
better than a 116 number which was there
for fi23 so hence in that context I
think if you look at directionally I
think the movement of the industry
combin ratio seems to be on a positive
trajectory and that is where ICS Lombard
kind of gains a lot of support from
given the fact that whenever we see the
underlying combined ratio for the
marketpl out positively we do see
pockets of opportunities for us to be
able to kind of disproportionately
outgrow the market and it is in that
context when you look at it for this
this quarter I think against an industry
growth of roughly at about 133% or there
above our growth was closer to about 20%
so we had a significant outperformance
uh relative to the market and this has
kind of largely played through across
the key lines of preferred segments for
us and in that context when I want when
I have to speak for how the pricing
environment is playing out I think let's
take the case of Health for example I
think uh and within Health if I were to
look at the employer employee or let's
say the corporate Health space now
that's a segment which historically has
been obviously elevated in terms of the
combined ratios for the market and hence
to that extent the pricing discipline
has not been great but over the last I
would say clearly the last 12 to 24
months I think the pricing environment
has clearly seen a positive change as in
to say that things have improved in
terms of pricing and hence as I said for
I Lombard it's a great opportunity and
that's again the reason why relative to
the industry growth of uh what we had
seen in that segment I think is Lombard
has had a significant outperformance uh
at a price at which we are kind of
comfortable with so hence to that extent
I think that pricing environment for
that segment seems to be playing out
quite well uh if you look at on the
retail Health side I think again very
recently from an Isis Lombard standpoint
we launched a Health Insurance Solutions
Elevate uh which kind of largely keeps
in mind uh the customer requirements uh
in terms of both the coverages as well
as at the price at which it is kind of
made available at I think we believe I
think the the book that we are
positioned at on the retail Health
broadly should take us to a loss ratio
of anywhere closer to about 70% or there
about so hence to that extent I think
the pricing regime that is playing out
on retail health for is Lombard seems to
be largely okay on motor I think again
as I said while the industry combined
ratios has improved I think given the
fact that there is an improvement in the
combin and hence to that extent for is
Lombard we have been able to kind of see
an improvement in the growth numbers on
Commercial lines that's the last segment
that I will talk about in the context of
pricing that's a segment which we have
which has seen slightly a bit of a
challenge in terms of the pricing
environment play out in the market and
that's a reason relative to the other
segments where we had an outperformance
on Commercial lines our growth has
largely been in line with industry
growth and that's exactly the thought
process that Isis Lombard has
historically been exhibiting as in to
say that whenever there are pricing
challenges then at that point of time we
take a slightly calibrated approach
[Music]